Ladies and gentlemen, put your hands
together for Ali Sadi.
[music]
[cheering]
Hey
You know, it's certain things in this
world that um that make me laugh, right?
The funniest statement in the world is
this to me. I don't care who say it,
when I hear it, I'm going to fall out
laughing. You know I know karate, right?
>> [laughter]
>> It just tickles me to death because my
daddy my daddy
um this was his saying. My daddy would
say this out of nowhere. You know I know
karate
and nobody ever questioned it
because and I I've never seen my daddy
do no karate.
I never seen him watch a karate movie.
He didn't own no karate shoes. He just
and you know everybody owned a pair of
them karate shoes and he never even
bought me no karate shoes. Talking about
he no karate. The the thing about it was
nobody would question it because my dad
is 6'3 and he wore boots all the time.
So that make him 6'4 6'5. You know what
I'm saying? And I saw my daddy do this
one day. Him and this dude was arguing.
My daddy said
and dude just backed off. I SAID, "MAN,
DON'T I'LL BE IN MY MIND. DON'T DON'T
LET HIM DO THAT TO you cuz I know this
man don't know no karate." I know my
daddy didn't know karate, but nobody
ever questioned it. Okay? And my dad had
to be the funniest person I've ever met
in my life. And I'm grateful for cuz
okay my daddy wasn't I'm not going to
say he not he wasn't the best daddy. He
was not ideal.
I'm just going to throw that out there.
He was not ideal. But I am grateful
for the time that we had. You know he my
daddy I'm all these stories is about to
be about my daddy cuz my mama my mama
think that um and she she about right.
My mama think I'm a good man because of
her.
No, I'm a responsible man because of my
mama. I'm a good man because of my
daddy. Cuz And I'm not talking about cuz
he was a good man. I'm talking about I
just never want to do none of the [\h__\h]
that he did.
NO. NO. Y'ALL DON'T UNDERSTAND. THIS
[\h__\h] WAS off the chain. Do you
understand?
and and my my daddy's decisions in life
are still haunting me
right now. Okay, let me I'm going to
start I'm not even going to start. I was
going to start. I'm going to tell y'all
this first cuz y'all need to understand
where I'm at with this. I'm in the club
last year. I'm in the club last year. Me
and my road manager Dre. This is me in
the club. Um,
and Drake Dre standing by me and I I
just dance in the club by myself. I'm
just [laughter]
I don't need no help. I'm just in there
with my thing just
and then I look up and this dude this
dude is looking at me
[laughter]
and I turn. I say, "Dre,
old boy over there looking at me.
If I uh catch him looking at me a little
longer, I'm going to go over there and
I'mma say something." Dre like, "Man,
who looking at you?" I said, "Nigga, I
just told you somebody looking at me.
Listen to me.
I'm in here moving my hips and [\h__\h] I
don't like no [\h__\h] looking at me while
I'm moving my hips, [\h__\h]
I don't know, [\h__\h] Don't look at me,
[\h__\h]
I felt vulnerable. I felt vulnerable.
[\h__\h] looking at me while my hips
moving. I don't like that [\h__\h]
But, but I'm a R&B. I I love R&B. to
these R&B songs. The DJ keep playing R&B
songs and I'm like, "Oh, don't do that
to me right there."
[laughter]
So then one of these little these little
line dance to me a line dance. Come on.
I'm in
and I'm in the corner trying to get it.
I'm like, "This [\h__\h] hard.
So, and I and and I keep I look over and
old boy still looking at me.
So, I say, "Dre, stay right here. I'm
going to go see what the time it is." I
walk over. I say, "Um,
say my man.
Um, bro, you you you um got a lot of eye
contact coming over there about me, bro.
Um, what's all that about? He saying, he
said, I'm looking at you. I said, for
what?
You know, my back got big immediately.
And then the man hit me cuz he sitting
down. He talking about cuz I think we
got something in common.
I was like, "Nigga, no, we don't got
nothing in common, [\h__\h] besides we
black and in this club. That's it."
He said, "Man, um, can I talk to you
outside?" I said, "You damn sure can.
Come on. Come on out here."
We get outside. Oh, boy. About 6'3.
About 63. But that don't mean nothing to
me. I I don't have no weight class and
no height class. I'm I'm
He said, "Man, I just um I'm looking at
you
cuz um I think me and you have the same
father."
I said, "No, you don't look like my
daddy." But the [\h__\h] do though a little
bit. You do. The [\h__\h] do look like my
daddy a little bit, too.
do this [\h__\h] do.
But I'm I'm I'm still my jaw tight. I'm
like, "No, you don't look like my dad,
nigga." He said, "Um, no, I think um we
got the same father." I said, "No, bro.
It's just um it's us four." I'm saying,
"It's my older sister. She 53,
you know what I'm saying? I'm um 51."
And this [\h__\h] going to tell me, "Well,
I'm 52." [\h__\h] don't be trying to add
no numbers in, [\h__\h] That don't mean
[\h__\h]
Trying to be in between us with the 52
[\h__\h] You should have said your age
first, [\h__\h] Don't you trying to
somebody? No, I'm I'm I'm 52. I'm born
in November.
I'm looking I'm I'm trying to calculate
my sister's August.
This [\h__\h] talking about November. I'm
October.
My little brother, he different though.
My little brother, he we we met him and
I was 18 when I met this [\h__\h]
He he September. And now um my my
youngest sister, which my dad my daddy
was trying to stay in line with me. Um
my oldest son is 31. Um my brother 34.
My oldest daughter 26. My youngest
sister 23. He trying to still stay
young. You know what I'm saying? Cuz you
know he know karate. So he know.
And I say say, "Bro, um I don't I don't
think so." Somebody
um I ain't saying I don't want nothing
from you. I know who you are. I don't
want nothing from you. But um I think
that we got the same daddy. And it's not
like I'm trying to get some people. I
never met the [\h__\h] Now, now right
there, I'm tight. I get tight. I say,
"Nigga, what you It don't matter if you
met him or not, [\h__\h] You trying to
claim him right now.
You better" I said, "Bro, you better
watch your tone when you talking about
Lenny Gains." Cuz um even though he
wasn't the best father, we loved him,
homeboy. He talking about, "Man, I never
really met him. My mama just told me
about it." I said, "Who your mama?"
and he said this lady named Denise.
>> I'm know I'm thinking in my mind not the
Denise
>> that came out of her. [clears throat]
Your mama Denise, huh? I said, "Bro, I I
don't know, man. You we may listen, bro.
You may be in here drinking. You know, I
know I didn't had me a little margarita.
Um, bro, we we can just give me your
number, dog. We'll talk tomorrow. He
gave me his number and he walked off. He
walked off and I turned to Dre. I said,
"Dre, this [\h__\h] walked just like my
daddy."
Next day he called me cuz I text him and
he called me and I said, "Hey, man. Um,
we got to figure out, you know, if you
are or you're not. I told my older
sister. My older sister straight up
said, "I ain't [\h__\h] with it."
Off the top, I say, "I'mma get a picture
of him and I'mma send it to you so you
can see him." Man, I sent that picture
of my sister cuz my sister's on she own
one. She ain't I still ain't [\h__\h]
with
I sent it to my little brother. My
little brother like [\h__\h] Yeah.
He looked just like us.
And I said, "Man, I don't I don't really
know."
Um, [clears throat]
I text him again. I said, "Hey, man.
Send me a picture of your mama
cuz this going this going to clear it up
for me." You know what I'm saying? And I
said, "Before you send me a picture of
your mama, send me a picture of your
feet.
I need to see this [\h__\h] feet. All of us
got the same feet. If you got my grandma
feet, then you you us.
And I'm thinking he ain't going to do
that. This grown ass 52-y old man going
to send me a picture of feet. That [\h__\h]
feet was lotioned up when he sent him to
this [\h__\h] feet was smooth and black as
hell. I say, "Yeah, this [\h__\h] might got
our feet, dog. He got our feet.
But I need to see this mama
>> cuz I know what my daddy like. I seen
all my daddy little Jones. I know what
he like. She got to be somewhere between
411 and 53.
Cinnamon brown,
long natural hair.
He sent this picture.
I looked at that picture and I called my
sister and my brother on through it. I
said, "Hey, we got a new brother."
Cuz this is damn show our brother. Now,
now I'm still finding out about kids.
Somebody walked up to me the other day
and said, "Hey,
you might be my brother." I said, "Oh
shit."
Cuz my daddy was was I don't know if
y'all you got to appreciate what he was.
This man was insane. Okay, so another
story about my daddy.
>> Huh?
>> Who said I can't hear you?
>> You can't hear me.
>> You got to turn that miracle ear up if
you want to hear this. And nobody else
complaining besides one person. I can't
hear you. [\h__\h]
Well, don't look at me. Look in your
seat like this. You go.
We recording something, lady. You can't
be holl [\h__\h]
Tap the person in front of you. What do
you say?
They talking about his daddy.
when um
when I went to go live
with my daddy
can't satisfy everybody.
So when I was living with my father, you
know, cuz I made a decision at 10 to go
live with my pops and my pops had a
different way of parenting. He was not
ready.
He really wasn't ready to be no parent.
That's just straight up. My My daddy was
really just using me.
No, y'all don't understand. My This This
was his go-to. He'll come come home with
a lady and he'll be like, "Yeah, you see
what I'm doing? Taking care of my son."
I'm like, "Nigga, I've been here 3
weeks, [\h__\h] What are you talking
about, [\h__\h] I don't even know you like
that. What you talking about?
Don't you bringing me into your little
conversation on boy now. But he was my
daddy was tricking know I told y'all
before my daddy had me selling these
pills and um for him when he was gone
and he was out my daddy also sold
cocaine powdered cocaine, right? My
daddy started the carrier service
downtown. My my daddy was the first Door
Dash.
1979 my daddy was first Door Dash. you
you would you would page him and say you
need something he bring it to you. So
you know he was bringing folk lawyers
cocaine downtown. Um so and and it was
called nose candy back then. That's when
it was called nose candy. You know what
I'm saying? Some of the old players in
here know you do like that. You know
nose candy. Right. So um my daddy will
forget to give me lunch money sometimes.
You know he just leave and he forget.
So, it was I remember it was October and
um this this um drugstore called Ekers
Drugs used to sell assorted bags of
candy, right? And so I bought some of
the candy after Halloween and I
separated all the stuff in the candy.
They had now ladies, blow pops, Jolly
Ranch, and I'm selling candy at school,
right? So, and I'm selling candy at
school for at least a month, month or
two. And Miss Cuttingham is the
principal. Miss Cuttingham confiscated
my candy and my money.
>> Okay.
And and she called my father. And this
is the worst thing in the world. It's
like it's like this. They called him to
come up to the school and he mad at me
cuz I'm interrupting his day.
He either Yeah. I'm Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. He come in. Hey. Yeah. Them people
didn't call me
I got to come down to your little school
in the morning and [\h__\h] I got things to
do. God damn. You got me coming down
there. Don't worry about catching a
little bus of walking. I'm going to take
you to school. And so we we riding it
all all the way. He met Yeah. I can't
believe these folk didn't got me down
here.
>> I said, "Man, um they just I got some
stuff confiscated. You around here
getting [\h__\h] confiscated?
I said, "Yeah, she just took my candy."
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I'm f to see what's
going on. We We get in the office and he
in there just being too fly. He Yeah.
What's happening? What's happening with
y'all?
And before he even get back there with
Miss Cunningham, it's a secretary. And
he in there, he like, "What's up, little
brown skin?" I'm
man, just see the lady and let's get out
of here. You know, I'm just I'm just I I
[laughter] CAN'T BE NICE. DAMN.
SO, he getting there with with the lady,
Miss Miss Kam. He So, um what what what
brings me down here? This how he talk.
What brings me down here? He said, um I
just want to let you know that the
school is a nonprofit
organization.
You cannot sell things at the school. He
said, "Well, [\h__\h] y'all be sending that
box of chocolate home and [\h__\h] What's
up?
That world famous. He can sell that
world famous [\h__\h]
That's That was my first That was my
first little door to door sales.
You want it with almonds or without
almonds? A dollar."
So my they didn't confiscated my candy
and Miss Cunningham pulls out this big
bag of candy and said yes this is what
he has been selling at school and my
daddy like okay
[laughter]
here selling candy here. Okay. And then
she pulls out this big bag of change.
And now my daddy is interested
and he slides
the change towards him
and Miss Cuttingham pulls the change
back. She's like, "Hey, this is he's
been making money up here and he can't
do this." My dad like, "Okay, all right.
So, um um he will not be doing that any
longer." Okay, we we we good. We good.
Okay. And then she slides the bag of
candy and say, "Hey, you can take this
home." And my daddy said,
"What about that change?
Is that us or that or that shop?"
She said, "No, I'm I'm going to give
that to you, too." So, my daddy got the
bag of chain. We in the car riding home.
My daddy is on my neck. I can't believe
your ass and got busted down here
selling candy.
The whole time I'm thinking,
"But you sell notes candy, though."
We get home, he coming there. Hey man,
[laughter]
listen here him. Don't have me come back
down that goddamn school. You take that
candy and you sell that candy off
premises if you need to sell something.
All y'all be on the bus and walking home
and [\h__\h] You sell it to them on the bus
and all that. And I said, "Um, hey,
what about that bag of change?
My daddy got tight with me. He came in.
So, you want the little bag of chain and
[\h__\h] Yeah. Take your little old money.
Take your little money and don't ask me
for no goddamn lunch money. I said, I I
hadn't been
asking you for lunch money. He said,
"Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. So, you ain't
going to pay me nothing for my gas
filing down there.
He going to tell me I'm the one got your
money back.
I said, "How much you want?" She said,
"How much you willing to give me?"
My father
was very different. Very different. He
would leave me with his brothers
and my uncles are not
people that you leave a child with
because they don't have no they don't
they didn't have no regulation on what
they would do in front of me. And so I'm
a I'm a different person because I've
been left with people who had no type of
responsibility for what a young child
would see. I'm 10 years old and my daddy
left me with my uncle Mac, which is my
favorite uncle on his side of the
family. My uncle Mac.
Um, look here.
You going to roll with me all day today.
He drove a Mercury Cougar.
Drove a Mercury Cougar. Long blue joint.
And he had pillows in the back of it.
And the pillows said black mac in the
back.
And so what I perceive still to this day
as a gangster is different from what
young boys perceive as a gangster.
Gangsters that I saw had on suits every
day. They dressed up dress shoes. They
they was they look like everybody else
in society. And my uncle M was um he was
a gangster and he this how this how he
walk. Look at come on. Let's roll.
And we in the car. We in the car and my
uncle Mac,
[snorts] we riding and he see this dude
go in the corner store. My uncle man,
hold on. How you get out of that?
And he backed he backed up. He backed up
in the street. He said, "Look here. I'm
going to run in the store real quick."
And he said this saying that every child
and every person in my family has heard.
And the first time I heard it, it was
from my grandmother. You know what I'm
saying? Because this because this is
when you couldn't take kids in the
liquor store. My my uncle Matt grabbed
his hammer and took his jacket off and
looked me in my face. Say, "Hey, I'm
about to run in here real quick. Don't
let nobody kidnap your ass."
First time I ever heard it was from my
grandmother.
I'm 6 years old with my grandmother. I'm
six. She about to go. My grandmother
drank gin. So you couldn't take kids in
a liquor store back then. So she about
to go in this liquor store. My
grandmother get out and roll and she
look back in the window. Look here.
I'm about to go in the liquor store.
When I come back, your ass better be in
the car. You understand me?
Don't let nobody kidnap your ass. So,
I'm just in the car.
I'm six. I see this man in a suspicious
van.
I roll the window down.
I said, "Hey, if you think about
kidnapping me, it ain't going to happen.
It's a lady in that liquor store that
I'm way more scared of than you."
And I don't know. I don't know. I got to
ask. I got to ask um men that's in here
that's over 50. If you're over 50, make
some noise if you're over 50.
I just got I just got a question. Were
curves higher
back then? Were they higher back then?
Cuz in my mind, I think they had to be
because my uncle M when he got out the
car, Uncle M, he got he got his suit
jacket off and he got the hammer and he
walking like this and he get to the curb
and he jumped up.
In my mind, curve got to be higher
because my uncle is 6'3. WHY WOULD HE BE
JUMPING UP A CURVE? He that [\h__\h]
And he is in that store. He's in the
store maybe 45 seconds. 45 seconds. And
he come running out the store. It's like
a run skip
cuz he got on dress shoes. He like
[clears throat]
and
and he jumped in the car and threw the
hammer in the back and handed me a pile
of bloody money
>> and he said, "Here, count that for me."
And burnt off. [laughter]
And I'm thinking,
"Did my uncle just rob the store?"
No. He I hear him mumbling to himself.
He said, "Yeah, [\h__\h] Kenny
think he gonna owe me money around here
buying [\h__\h] Got to pay me first.
I don't think that's how you supposed to
collect money, sir."
And I'm telling y'all that story to lead
into this now. That was when I was 10.
11. I'm 11 years old. I'm at my dad's
job with my dad. 2600 block of Louisiana
Street in Houston. We at this building
in the Sallyport
and um my dad would get mad at me about
things that he has, you know, subjected
me to. I'm in the car and my dad is
outside the car. Um him and this guy,
they talking
and then they start arguing
and the dude pushed my daddy
and my daddy pushed him back. Watch out.
Now,
you know I know karate.
Him and my daddy start tussling. My
daddy slip cuz my daddy got on dress
shoes. He slipped and the dude jump on
top of my daddy and he's about to hit my
dad in the face. I'm in my dad's car and
in my dad's car there's a hammer.
And before that man hit my daddy in the
face, I got out
and hit that man with that hammer. And
the man leaned over and my daddy looked
right in my face and said, "Godamn it,
you didn't hit my best worker in the
goddamn head with a hammer.
What type of [\h__\h] are you on?
We argue every Friday about this money.
Give me this goddamn hand. Where you
learn some [\h__\h] like that at?
We get home and
let me give you another little piece of
this story. My uncle Mac
never liked
rap music. He never liked rap music
until MC Hammer came out.
And I don't even think he knew a whole
song. All he knew was just one part of
MC Hammer. And he would say it all the
time. If you front on the Hammer, you
will be rewarded.
We get home
and my daddy is talking to my uncle M.
He's like, "Man, can you believe this
little violent little [\h__\h]
He got to stop watching that TV. He
picking up [\h__\h]
One man say, "Well, what happened, man?
I'm out there tussling. You know what
kid get?" He done hit this [\h__\h] in the
head with a hammer. I say, "Where you
get some [\h__\h] like that from?"
And my uncle Max said
and looked at me and whipped his eyes to
my If you run on the hammer, you
terrible. [clears throat]
This is terrible.
My daddy
I I grew up never liking birthday
parties. I never like birthday parties
cuz I realized that my daddy would be
using my birthday party just to get back
with my mama.
it. It's my birthday, so my daddy going
to come over and try to get back with my
mama on my birthday. And I never like
birthday parties, but and and it was
crazy thing is me growing up. Um I
remember when my birthday party was was
a dual party. It was a dual party. The
first part was for me and then it turned
real grown.
I'm I'm 6 years old and we we we having
a party and I knew I should have known
something cuz it was too many grown
people.
It was a lot of grown people at a
child's party and they would come
dressed up. They was like, "Why you
dressed up [\h__\h] Wait for me."
And my sister, she knew cuz my sister's
older than me. She knew. I remember
going upstairs
just to pee. Went upstairs to pee. And
then I came back downstairs and my
sister stopped me and said, "Come here.
It ain't your party no more."
She said, "Come on now. You you smell
that different smell down there. And the
music is different. It's this song." And
I love this song to this day. It's by
Marvin Gay. You know, I used to go out I
used to go out and party
and stand around. Yeah, I can't sing,
but I know that's the song.
And I'm standing right on the the basin
of the steps. And my uncle Alfred, my
daddy's brother,
he come by and he dancing with this
woman named Rosalyn.
Yeah, Rosalyn.
Roslin changed my whole scope of what I
wanted in a woman.
Roslin made it different. At first, I
used to just like what my daddy liked,
something cinnamon brown short. But
Alfred came in there with Roslin. Roslin
jet black.
Jet black. And she thin. And she ain't
wearing no panties with them slacks.
Huh.
That lady booty was juicy. You know what
I'm saying? I'm 6 years old. I'm like, I
like that, [\h__\h] I like that.
[laughter]
I like [\h__\h] baby.
And y'all going to say this is the late
'7s and men still dressing a little
different than what they dress like now.
Men had a lot of masculinity, you know,
back then. And my uncle, he I'm I'mma
describe these outfits. My uncle um
Alfred
got on some black slacks with no no belt
loops just like mine right now. No belt
loose. They and they button over here
somewhere.
And he has on a blouse. I don't care
what he say. He has on a blouse.
He got on the blouse.
It's very silky.
and it's buttoned down to his navl
and he dancing with Rozley
and he look at me. He's like, "Nephew,
what's wrong with you?
Why you looking sad at your party?"
He said, "Um,
man, I I I wanted some of my cake." He
said, "Shit, get you some.
I said, "I want some, but it's a dude
over there eating my cake with his
hand."
And the dude, let me tell you what he
got on. Let me tell you what he got on.
He got on some blue slacks
with a um a fishnet
wife beater.
Got him on a fishnet white bit. He had
these little rectangle glasses. And this
[\h__\h] over there eating my cake with his
bare hand.
And my uncle look over there. He
>> [laughter]
>> He said, "Shit is somebody over there
eating your cake
with his bare hand. Let me let me go
over there and talk to this [\h__\h] real
quick." And I watched my uncle dance
through a whole crowd of people. What's
up, boy? I'm going to be right back. I'm
going be right back. I'm going be right
back.
And the music is loud and you can't
really hear what's being said, but I um
I know body language. I know body
language. My uncle, get over there.
and dude like
and I watched two men
dance to an audience to follow each
other outside.
Me and my sister ran upstairs.
We ran upstairs because they outside.
They were outside in in front of the
house. We ran upstairs and opened the
window. Now we can hear.
And my uncle Alfred said, "Hey, [\h__\h]
man, what type of monkey [\h__\h] you in
there doing eating [\h__\h] cake
with your bare goddamn hands? This ain't
even your cake, [\h__\h] And who invited
you to the party?" And old boy ain't
bagging down. He said, "Man, I eat what
type of [\h__\h] cake I want to
eat, [\h__\h] And what you going to do
about it?" Uncle say, "Nigga, you know
what I'm going to do? You know what I'm
I'mma do something like this?" [\h__\h]
Knocked the old boy out by a Pontiac
Sunfire. I don't know who called that
was.
party. My uncle came back in the house.
I'm on the steps. My uncle come by me
dancing with the cake.
You You want some cake? I said, "No, I
still don't want no cake."
My daddy. My daddy come out there. Hey
man,
there's a [\h__\h] outside laying down by
the Pontiac Sunfire.
My dad was um [clears throat] he was
just a he was a different type of
person. And I got to respect him for
what he um he was. And as he got older,
I had to help my pops. And I and you
know, you find out things about your
parents that you didn't um you didn't
know. So, I used to be in the streets. I
used to be a street pharmaceutical rep,
which is very frowned upon, right?
I come on I come on the block. I'm on
this block called Woodfair. I come on
the block and these young boys are
bragging about they just robbed these
two old dudes.
I said, "Word?" I said, "What y'all
get?" He like, "Shit, let me show you.
Let me show." So they pull out the stuff
and I said, "Y'all
put that put that in that bag right
there."
They say, "Damn, you going you going to
take our stuff?" I said, "You took it
from somebody, didn't you,
man? What's up?" I mean, put the [\h__\h] in
the bag, bro. Just put it in the bag,
man. God damn. I said, "Man, I ain't
going to say the [\h__\h] again, bro. You
know how I get down. I'm looking at you.
Put the [\h__\h] in the bag.
and we going to call it even. Young boys
put the [\h__\h] in the bank, man. God damn,
[\h__\h] You just just around here
roughizing the [\h__\h] I'm like, "All
right, boy." So, um, take [snorts] the
bag and I go to my pop's house.
I walk up. I said, "Hey,
your [\h__\h] bro."
He said, "Man,"
I said, "Was you over there
smoking, nigga?"
My daddy with this other dude talking
about, "No, I mean this I'm with this
[\h__\h] This [\h__\h] got me robbed and
shit."
I said, "All right." Cuz you know over
there it don't nothing beat but do fines
over there in warfare. Bro, you
shouldn't be over there. And if this
[\h__\h] smoking, you shouldn't be with it.
And dude ain't saying nothing. My daddy
just Yeah, this thing got me over there.
I said he asked for a ride and then I'm
over there with this [\h__\h] All of a
sudden, we we pent up.
All right, cool. So I I bounce and then
3 days later I just happened to be at my
mama's crib and I say, "Mom, you know
something? Daddy got robbed and you know
I got his stuff back. I knew the dudes."
And she said, "He was probably out there
smoking."
I said, "No, he don't he don't smoke no
dope." My mom look me in my face say,
"Boy, I done put your daddy in rehab
twice."
I'm hot. I go back to my daddy house. I
said, "Hey, man. I thought you said you
wasn't [\h__\h] smoking." You know what
I'm saying? I heard that you was
smoking. He talking about who told you
that your mama.
Man, your mama violate my hippo rights,
dog.
always saying some [\h__\h]
violating your hyper right
and you sign a contract. You ain't
supposed to say nothing about somebody
being in rehab.
I said, "Man, you got to stop you got to
stop this smoking [\h__\h] dog." He's like,
"Man, I ain't smoke that much."
So then they get clean. My pops get
clean, right? And
I'm 43 years old. My mama called me to
her house. I get over there. I say,
"What's up, mama?" She said, "I need you
to do me a favor." I said, "What you
got?" So, I need you to get your daddy
to sign these divorce papers.
What?
I said, "Y'all not divorced?
Y'all ain't been together since I was
like four or five years old." Talking
about he would never sign the papers. He
would never sign the papers. I said,
"What?"
So, I got to go to Alexander, Louisiana
from Houston to get my daddy to sign the
paper. And I I didn't tell him why. I
called him. I said, "Hey, man. I'm going
to run down there and see." He said,
"Good. You being a good son, come see
your father."
I get down to Louisiana.
My daddy looking good. I said, "Hey, um,
I need you to sign some papers for me."
He talking about [\h__\h] I didn't know
anything for you, baby. What? What? You
going to leave me something?
No.
I said, "Ain't you supposed to be
leaving me some?" "Hey, man, you the one
with all the success and shit." I said,
"Yes."
I say, "Now, um,
mama need you to sign these papers."
What papers?
I said, "Divorce papers?" That man said,
"Ah, your mama still on that bullshit."
And then going to holl OUT, "JOE,
BRING ME A COKE in here." This [\h__\h]
been with Joanne for 15 years. This
[\h__\h] said my my mama is still on some
[\h__\h] He said, "Man, you got to get
that [\h__\h] notorized." I said, "Man, my
partner, a notary, he wrote down here
with me." "Oh, so you just got
everything together, huh?"
I said, "Man, I just need you
to sign the papers
so I can get out of here." He said,
"Man, this some bullshit."
Hey, man. Man, give give me a pen, man.
Give me a pen. Cuz I'm I'm I'm just
hurt. I'm just hurt.
You just a hide gun for your mama. Huh?
Just a hide gun.
And he he signing the papers still
saying she talking about, man,
this is the end of a era.
>> [laughter]
>> So he signed the papers. My man
notorized them. And that man looked me
right in my face. I'm getting I said,
"Man, I'm going to go, bro. Um, I'm I'm
going to come back down and visit you."
My daddy looked at me and said, "Tell
your mama, don't give up on love.
I said, "This is the craziest person
I've ever met in my life."
My dad My dad had a thing about
how he dressed.
My dad always wore tailor made suits.
This is when he was when he was on his
note. When he was on his note cuz he was
a It's not a lot of men can say how they
how they felt about their pops. I really
wanted to look like this man. He was
tall, dark, jet black, had um a lot of
charisma about himself, but he just
wasn't an ideal
father.
My dad asked me one time, I'm sitting at
his house and my daddy said,
"Man, why you don't never say nothing
bad about your mama on stage,
out of nowhere, out of nowhere,
I said, "Man, um, it's not
it's not a lot
Bad stuff to say about my mama. About
that say [\h__\h]
You must don't realize I knew your mama
before she was your mama.
I said, "Man, I I don't I don't know no
bad stuff about my mama." My daddy said,
"You know something? Stay right here.
I'll be right back."
My daddy
walked back in
and put a picture down upside down. The
picture was upside down. He put it down
there to my Yeah. Turn that over.
And I said to my dad, I said, "Hey,
Say, "Bro, I love you, D. I love you
with everything in me, but I I I promise
you, if I turn this pitch over
and my mama is in any type of
compromising position,
if my mama is doing anything that she is
unblaused, [\h__\h] I'm trying to tell
you, it's going to be some [\h__\h] in here.
I'm trying to tell you cuz you you ain't
got to do me like that. You ain't got to
put my eyes on no [\h__\h]
My daddy man, just turn the pitch off.
Just turn the pitch off. Yeah, just turn
it on.
My mama's not even in this picture.
Do you understand? My mama's not even in
the picture.
It's a picture of me
and him.
I'm on my daddy's shoulders. I'm about 5
years old. I'm on my daddy's shoulders
and he I said, "Man, what is this got to
do
with my mama?" Talking about Yeah. Yeah.
You see the picture, huh? Yeah. Where
you at?
I said, "I it looked like a a concert."
Yeah. How did you get there?
I said, "I don't know. I've never seen
this picture before." Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
You want to You want to hear a story,
Mr. Story, man? I got a story for you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Your
mama, your mama called me, right? And
it's a Saturday. She said, "Hey, um, can
you keep your son?" I said, "Hey,
Carol."
That's my mama name, Carol. Said, "Hey,
Carol, I got something to do tonight.
I'll keep that boy Sunday." My mama
said, "Well, I need you to really keep
him on Saturday." My My daddy said,
"Look here, Cara.
I done told you I got something to do
Saturday night that I [clears throat]
can't cancel.
I keep that boy Sunday
now. My mama had been calling my daddy
and he wasn't answering the phone
according to him
when answering the phone. Right
[sighs]
now, I'mma stop this story and I'm going
to give you another story before I go to
this story.
I know that I am
a better father
than my father was. And I'm supposed to
be. I'm supposed to be just by my son's
first concert
and my first concert with my father.
My son Hassan,
he's 11.
His first concert was Earth, Wind, and
Fire. And he asked to go. He asked to
go. My My son came in to me and said,
"Father,
cuz he's very upper crust."
He said, "I would like to attend a
concert."
I said, "Hassan,
what concert would you like to attend?"
He said, "I would like to go see the
elements."
And I teared up. I teared up.
If my son want to go see the elements
and I said, "Wait,
who are the elements, Hassan? Is it some
little white internet group that you've
been listening to?"
Hassan said, "No, father.
They're formerly known as Earth, Wind,
and Fire.
I immediately ran and got them tickets.
I wanted to get them tickets for me and
my son. Me and my son going to see
Earth, Wind, and Fire. He is 11. He's 11
years old. We went to this first
concert. Me and him, we going. We get to
the concert. Hassan is the youngest
person in this whole entire concert. And
I know that for facts because I am the
second youngest person.
Everybody else in that concert,
do you remember
it was so much oxygen that goddamn
concert?
old people rolling in with my see that
it's a lot of oxygen
and I'm in there terrified cuz earth
wind got all type of pyro [\h__\h] going on
and I'm moving people oxygen core get
out
get your explosive ass from in the
That's my son's first concert.
Responsible. He with me.
Back to my father.
My daddy is telling me this story and he
telling me in detail. He say, "Man, I'm
getting ready for the concert." And I'm
in there, you know, I'm
I'm getting ready getting ready for the
concert. And my daddy is going to see
his favorite group, Parliament.
>> He's going to see Parliament. And this
is his This is his This is his group.
This is when George Clinton was Dr.
Funkenstein.
Yeah. This is when he would come out of
a mother ship.
And he come out and his hair was crazy.
He had on boots. He come out.
I'm He kicked the door open first. He
come out.
>> My daddy say he is getting ready for
this concert.
Got his outfit on.
He um walking out the door and he he
walked out and he latched. He had this
gate. He closed the gate and he said he
hit a step and said and he turned around
and I am on the hood of his car.
He said your mom left you on the hood of
the car unattended [\h__\h] Unattended.
My daddy say he was pissed. Say, "I'm
mad as hell. I'm calling your mama.
She ain't answering the phone.
It's 20 minutes until the concert.
I said, "Shit,
I got my outfit on already."
>> My daddy said he ran upstairs. He had no
intentions on wearing no leather trench
coat.
He said he went upstairs and got his
trench coat.
He put me in the car. They get to the
place which was the Astrodome.
This was the This concert was being held
at the Astrodome and man he said he
holding me and he looking for a weak
link at the tickets.
He say, "You see this dude that he think
ain't paying attention that cold?" My
daddy said, "Get on my back real quick
and hold on tight and don't say
nothing."
He say, "My daddy came over. I had a
plan. Good. I come up. We won't
let I hear that." What was you good? You
say, did he say he danced his way
backwards into the arena? We want the
funk.
He got me in the concert and then let me
down.
He said we he got he got to his where
his little section was cuz they didn't
have seats. They had where you it was
just open. He said, "You want to know
how you got on my shoulders?" I said,
"Hey, man. I don't I don't want to know
this story no more."
He says, "I'm in the goddamn concert."
And then the mother ship land. They come
out.
Everybody going crazy. They smoking
weed. Everybody smoking weed. And he in
that we
go. Then he look he he said he in there
dancing. And he turned around and said,
"What the hell is my damn song?
We want the funk.
>> And he said he looked down this road. He
said this white man was throwing me up
in there. We won't.
My daddy say he danced over there.
He said that's how I end up on his neck.
He said the whole concert I'm on his
neck and he say and you up there just
high as hell.
And I know I was high cuz my neck was
loose as hell in that picture.
I GOT THAT NOTHING WRONG WITH ME.
SOMETHING WRONG WITH MY DADDY.
The deal is this.
I tell these stories to people
so they can be grateful
for the time that you shared with your
parent whether it was they was good or
whether it was bad.
Cuz let me tell you something. Tell you
something.
February 14th,
2018,
days before my first special came out.
I had um usually I don't answer the
phone when I land somewhere. I wait till
I get to my hotel room. This particular
time, my pops called me when I landed in
LA.
I answered the phone. I said, "Man,
what's going on?" He said, "Man, [\h__\h]
man. I just called to check on Hassan's
chess game cuz my daddy played chess.
I've been playing since I was six." And
he he had met my son and he was trying
to teach Hassan to play chess. And he
wanted me to keep playing with him. So,
he called to check on his chess game.
And I said, "Man, I when I get back,
I'mma I'mma um spend some time playing
with him." He said, "Man, you do that,
man. you make sure you do that. And then
he's about to get off the phone and I
never feel like a kid with my dad, but
um my special is about to come out and I
asked him, I said, "Hey, man, did you
see the trailer for my special?" And he
said, "Now you know damn well I saw the
trailer for your special with that
little Michael Jackson spin you did on
there." I said, "That's Player. That's
Player.
That's Player." I said, "Man, I
appreciate you." Now, that's on the
13th. That was on the 13th. I am flying
back to Houston the next day cuz I just
went out to LA to do some press. My
alarm is set for 3:00 to get up. My
phone keeps going off. And I get up. I
said, "Damn, my alarm is tripping." But
it's not my alarm.
It's Joanne. and Joanne is calling me.
And I said, I answer the phone. I said,
"What's up, Joanne?" It's early in the
morning. She said, "Baby,
I want to give you something. I want to
tell you something about your father." I
said, "What's wrong with him? I just
talked to him like hours ago." He said,
"Baby, your father had a heart attack
and passed
right before my special came out." And
this is exactly what I said. I said,
"February 14th." I said, "Boy, this a
cold [\h__\h] right here."
Cuz my daddy knew that I hated
Valentine's Day. And we talking about
all the time how much I hated
Valentine's Day. I said, "This [\h__\h]
going to die [clears throat] on
Valentine's Day. Now I got to remember
this shit."
And I looked up. I said, "Boy, you're a
cold [\h__\h] man."
And what's crazy when I was getting
ready to walk out the hotel, a dude came
by playing we want the funk.
>> And I said,
"All right."
Cuz I was so grateful for the time that
I spent with him. The moral of the
story, my father, make sure y'all be
grateful to the people that you love all
the time, cuz you never know how long
you got with them. Ali Sadik. Thank
y'all.
>> [music]
>> Heat up
here.
[music]
[cheering]
>> [music]
>> Going home. We're going home.
Going home. [music] We're going home.
[singing]
Going home. We're going
[music and singing] home.
>> [music]